# **DANIEL ARCÉ**

### Senior Front-End Developer | darce.github.io

daniel.arce@gmail.com (646)506-8957, Brooklyn, NY

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a front-end developer with over twelve years of experience and a multidisciplinary education. I have a deep understanding of interaction design and a passion for accessibility. My skill in communicating effectively with product and executive stakeholders has led to roles in building interactive prototypes to drive product development.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Contextual Alt Text Plugin - Sole Developer & Product Designer (Independent project)

Feb 2024 — present

Developing a WordPress plugin to generate context-aware alternative text for images using a Large Language Model, improving accessibility for the visually impaired.

- · Independently define, prototype, and develop a minimum viable product (MVP) to validate the concept and gather initial user feedback.
- Implement Test-Driven Development (TDD) using **PHPUnit** to ensure code quality, maintainability, and a focused development approach.
- · Conduct research on WCAG standards and best practices for alternative text to ensure the plugin meets accessibility requirements.
- · Integrate a Large Language Model API to analyze image content and generate meaningful, context-aware descriptions.
- · Design and develop a user-friendly interface for the WordPress plugin, allowing users to easily manage and customize the generated alternative text.

#### Freelance Web Developer

Apr 2023 — present

- Extracted assets from a legacy Flash website, redesigned and developed barbarabeirne.com, a photo portfolio site (2023).
- Rebranded and developed a new site for bauhausdances.org with a custom-built WordPress theme (2023).

Professional Sabbatical - Personal Growth and Professional Development

Jul 2022 — Mar 2023

- · Classical portraiture and life drawing intensive, Grand Central Atelier, New York, Summer 2022
- Full-Stack Web Development, University of Helsinki Certificate, March 2023

#### Photoshelter - Senior Front-End Developer New York

Sep 2018 — Feb 2022

Photoshelter.com is a Cloud-based Digital Asset Management tool for creative teams, hosting over 1 billion files for 80,000 professionals. Research and Development team - Jan 2021 - Feb 2022

- · Prototyped a workflow automation interface. This prototype was the basis of a new feature launched later that year.
- · Proposed an image blur detection tool using client-side OpenCV. This working proof-of-concept allowed the company to measure interest in this tool.
- · Participated in cross-team discussions with our Chief Architect that steered the direction of new features and product requirements.

#### Production team - Sep 2018 - Jan 2021:

- · Spearheaded the adoption of Accessibility Standards and led the code audit, resulting in the acquisition and retention of key institutional clients.
- · Implemented keyboard navigation for nested collections, eliminating much of the Accessibility tech debt.
- · Contributed to the next version of the web app written in React, modernizing the current Polymer2 interface.
- Worked closely with product and UX designers to plan and develop new features.
- Automated unit tests with Mocha and Chai for Continuous Integration using Jenkins.
- · Mentored junior developers, emphasizing attention to Accessibility guidelines.

### Apple Inc - Senior Front-End Developer (contract) Sunnyvale Campus

Jul 2017 — Mar 2018

- · Converted static designs to responsive, pixel-perfect code for the media launch of the iPhone X.
- Collaborated with the marketing and design teams to realize projects for Apple.com.
- Prototyped and developed the first direct email by the Marketing Department using CSS3 animations, achieving a 90% open rate.
- · Authored automation tools for direct mail campaigns using Node.js, bash script, and Gulp.

## Creative Technologist, New York, Oslo, Toronto

2014 - 2017

"Texting Syria" is an art installation created in collaboration with photojournalist Liam Maloney. Along the gallery, images of Syrian refugees in a Lebanese camp are shown, while previously obtained conversations from these refugees are texted to gallery visitors.

- Built and deployed the texting app with the PHP Twilio SMS API.
- Presented at The Nobel Peace Center, Oslo (2017), Photoville in Brooklyn (2016), and Scotiabank's Nuit Blanche, Toronto (2014).

### Publicis North America - Senior Interactive Developer New York

Nov 2015 - Nov 2016

- Brought citirewards.com up to level AAA of the Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG)
- · Worked with designers and product managers to create web campaigns for clients, including Verizon, LG, and Colgate.

### Code and Theory - Senior Front-End Developer New York

Mar 2015 - Nov 2015

- Consulted and collaborated with UX designers and developers to build the motel6.com price management tool in EmberJS.
- Prototyped single-page web applications for Comcast in AngularJS.
- Automated building and deployment tasks for static sites with Gulp and Grunt.

## MSNBC - Senior Design Technologist and Front-End Developer New York

Oct 2013 - Mar 2015

- Iterated working Javascript prototypes during the ideation and design phase for msnbc.com/videos with a cross-disciplinary team.
- Authored Drupal modules in PHP, Javascript/jQuery, and CSS3 for msnbc.com.

#### Kirshenbaum Bond Senecal - Design Technologist and Front-End Developer New York

Jan 2013 - Oct 2013

- Promoted the use of object-oriented patterns in Javascript. This improved the maintainability of the codebase.
- Created and maintained static micro-sites for various clients, including Puma, BMW, and Bank of New York Mellon.

### The Huffington Post / AOL - UI Engineer New York

May 2011 - Nov 2012

· Worked with Front-End engineers to optimize the site's loading and rendering times, which resulted in a 30% improvement in loading times.

• Prototyped the new site-wide main navigation using jQuery and Javascript.

## **EDUCATION**

Full-Stack Web Development, University of Helsinki Certificate, March 2023

• React, Redux, and Node.js

### NYU Tisch School of the Arts, Master of Professional Studies, Interactive Telecommunications Program (ITP) New York, 2010

- Awarded entrance scholarship
- Studies focused on the intersection of Design and Technology

# Concordia University, BFA, Interdisciplinary Studies, Montreal

Focus on digital media production, video, and electro-acoustics